{
    "uid": "592319ba-7fd3-4322-ad14-1fa946fedc46",
    "title": "Windows Endpoint Analysis Challenge 1",
    "instructions": "<p>You've been assigned to remotely investigate a compromised Windows workstation as part of a live incident response scenario. The affected system has been imaged and all necessary forensic artifacts have been gathered. Your objective now is to investigate the scope of the compromise and identify any persistence mechanisms installed by the attacker.</p> <p>Use your endpoint analysis skills to conduct the investigation and answer the questions below.</p><h3>Challenge File:</h3><p><ul><li><code>03_Endpoint_Security/Windows/Challenges/challenge.exe</code></li></ul></p><p>To start the challenge, execute <code>challenge.exe</code> in an Administrator-level command prompt. Make sure to not close the program or window until after you've completed the challenge. However, you can temporarily minimize it. After running the executable, you can open additional command prompt windows to complete the investigation.</p><p>After completing the challenge, you can clean up and restore the system by terminating the <code>challenge.exe</code> process (Press Ctrl + C). Then, run <code>challenge.exe -revert</code>.</p>",
  
  
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Simulate the compromise by running <code>challenge.exe</code> in an Administrator-level command prompt. Make sure to not close the program or window until after you've completed the challenge. However, you can temporarily minimize it. Enter \"<b>done</b>\" to continue.",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter \"done\" to continue",
            "correct_answers": ["done"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What <b>port</b> is the <code>challenge.exe</code> malware listening on?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The <code>netstat</code> command can be paired with several useful options to display network connections and listening ports.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["50050", "port 50050"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>Process ID (PID)</b> of the malware? <i>This answer cannot be verified, but it's required for the next question(s).</i>",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The <code>netstat</code> command can be paired with several useful options to display network connections, listening ports, and their associated Process IDs (PIDs).",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here"
        },
        {
            "question": "List all of the loaded <b>DLL modules</b> for the listener's associated process. What are the names of the two DLLs that start with the letter <b>m</b>?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Read the help page for the (<code>tasklist /?</code>) command to figure out the option that can list a process' loaded DLL modules.",
            "placeholder": "Answer format: name, name",
            "correct_answers": ["mswsock.dll, msvcrt.dll", "msvcrt.dll, mswsock.dll", "mswsock.dll msvcrt.dll", "msvcrt.dll mswsock.dll"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>name</b> of the malware's <b>parent</b> process?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "There are several ways to find out this information. The <code>wmic</code> command can be used to pull back specific details about a process, including its parent's process name.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["cmd.exe"]
        },
        {
            "question": "List all the <b>shared resources</b> on the local system. What is the name of the <b>share</b> that the attacker created?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "The <code>net _____</code> command is your friend.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["xkalibur"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What path or resource does the attacker's share point to?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["C:\\Users\\tcm\\AppData\\Local\\Temp\\46d5b8556d0d3e30ec1"]
        },
        {
            "question": "The attacker created a <b>Run</b> entry to establish persistence on the system. What is the <b>full path</b> of the registry key?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "You can use the <b>Autoruns</b> utility (Sysinternals) to identify abnormal autorun entries. Or, you can query the well-known autorun entries manually using <code>reg query</code>.",
            "placeholder": "****\\********\\*********\\*******\\**************\\***",
            "correct_answers": ["HKEY_CURRENT_USER\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Run", "HKCU\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Run", "Computer\\HKEY_CURRENT_USER\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Run", "Computer\\HKCU\\SOFTWARE\\Microsoft\\Windows\\CurrentVersion\\Run", "HKEY_CURRENT_USER/SOFTWARE/Microsoft/Windows/CurrentVersion/Run", "HKCU/SOFTWARE/Microsoft/Windows/CurrentVersion/Run"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>name</b> of the malicious entry the attacker created in the previously identified registry key?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["CleanUpController"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the full file or image <b>path</b> that this registry entry points to?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["C:\\Users\\tcm\\Downloads\\wininit.exe"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the backdoor <b>service</b> installed by the attacker?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "You can use the <b>Autoruns</b> utility (Sysinternals) to identify abnormal services.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["WindowsActiveService"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the <b>START_TYPE</b> configuration of the service?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "Once you've identified the name of the backdoor service, you can use the <code>sc __</code> command to query its configuration.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["AUTO_START", "auto start", "autostart", "auto"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the full path to the service binary?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["C:\\Users\\tcm\\Documents\\svcbackdoor.exe"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the scheduled task created by the attacker?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "hint": "You can use the <b>Autoruns</b> utility (Sysinternals) to identify abnormal scheduled tasks. Or, you can query system tasks manually using the <code>schtasks</code> utility.",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["ayttpnzc", "\\ayttpnzc"]
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the full path to the executable that the scheduled task runs?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter your answer here",
            "correct_answers": ["C:\\Users\\tcm\\Downloads\\beac0n.exe"]
        },
        {
            "question": "At what time is the scheduled task set to run?",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "*:**:** **",
            "correct_answers": ["3:30:00 AM", "3", "3:30:00", "3:30 AM", "3AM", "3 AM"]
        },
        {
            "question": "Excellent work! Clean up and restore the system by terminating the <code>challenge.exe</code> process (Press Ctrl + C). Then, run <code>challenge.exe -revert</code>. Afterwards, enter \"<b>done</b>\" to continue.",
            "type": "text_input",
            "placeholder": "Enter \"done\" to continue",
            "correct_answers": ["done"]
        }
    ]
  }